so today's video we're going to try
something new uh basically I got a
Facebook message from this guy named
Steve uh paranos and he said uh the
girls at his gym uh they've been working
on their strong curves they think their
form could be better but uh basically
they just wanted to let me know that
they've been working hard on their form
and that uh they're big fans and they
love uh strong curves and uh and the
glute guy so I told him I'd film a video
video critiquing the form uh they look
good you can tell they've been working
hard but I've been doing this a really
long time so uh I thought I'd I'd offer
a video for feedback as this is very
useful so
uh first up we've got a single legegg
RDL uh and this is pretty good form um I
like people going down just below uh the
knees on these just like you would a
normal Romanian deadlift I like to look
at the tibia I like vertical tibia uh I
like to see that the head and uh neck
and spine are in a straight position if
people look up a little bit I'm not so
concerned about that some coaches are
very nitpicky and they want this neutral
head neck alignment some people like to
see the chin tucked I don't care so much
about that if they look up a little bit
so be it as long as they aren't like
cranked up looking straight up uh fully
hyperextended but uh but this lady looks
great head neck spine in good alignment
uh the tibia is pretty
vertical um and she's the most important
thing here she's keeping that bar very
close to her body the whole way through
and sitting
back uh and and keeping the spine arched
she's not rounding so this is great form
the only pointer that I have is that
this leg I would like to see this knee
straightened out and this leg locked
into full hip extension so ideally you
would go head neck spine leg just like
that all in a straight line because this
leg would be straightened out locked
that squeeze that glute of the the
non-working leg and lock the hip into
extension it it serves it as a better
counter counterbalance and it just looks
more aesthetically pleasing so again
great job uh vertical tibia she's
sitting back the bar skims the body
she's using her glutes to lock the
weight out but the only tip is that this
leg could be in full
extension um next
up we've
got a lady doing uh deficit reverse
lunges and uh form looks pretty good
here uh I will say
that she's got a very upright torso she
could lean just slightly more and then
have those arms straight down see our
arms are pushing forward the arms will
naturally tend to do that uh that's a
way it's actually a way of increasing
the hip extension moment and decreasing
the knee extension Moment by Shifting
the weight forward you increase the
distance the the the moment arm to the
hip decrease it to the knees so that's
that's a strategy make it more hip
dominant and less knee dominant but when
the weight gets really heavy your arms
are going to want to be more straight
down just because it's you're you're
going to be doing like a partial front
raise it's not going to happen when
you're holding on to really heavy weight
but you can do this create the same
effect just by leaning forward slightly
which does the same exact thing so again
this is good uh she takes a nice step
back sinks deep gets a nice stretch on
that glute but she could just lean
slightly more but this is she's pushing
through the heel uh takes a good step
back she's the right distance so
everything looks good here except maybe
she could lean a bit
more okay uh next up we've got a hip
thrust
and this looks good uh What I will say
is I look at the feet she's pushing
through the heels she's not rising up on
her toes the tibas are vertical here
that's another thing I look at she
reaches full hip extension you can tell
she's pushing those glutes upwards and
locking out in a full hip extension her
head and neck stay in pretty good
alignment here uh she's not cranking her
neck forward uh or look or uh leaning
back excessively however I will mention
that I'm okay with neck movement on this
I myself go into neck flexion a lot of
my clients do some of my clients lay
their head back on the bench uh into
extension just because they it relieves
their neck muscles and some keep it
neutral it looks more aesthetically
pleasing keeping it neutral but I'm more
concerned with full hip extension and uh
you know what the lumbar spine is doing
but she's nice and uh keeping the the
Torso flat she's
not uh you know putting her chest out
which would overarch her lumbar spine
and anterior pelvic uh anteriorly tilt
her pelvis so she's not doing that so
she's using glutes to to push the to
lock the weight out what only tip I
would say is uh those legs could be
spread apart more so take a wider stance
maybe a foot more apart and that would
be
ideal uh I'll also say that when the
okay here's the next lady doing hip hip
thrust this is a tall bench and when
it's a smaller bench I like to see the
weights touch the ground but in this
situation it's a very tall bench uh so
so I don't want those weights to touch
the ground I like that they're stopping
short but again vertical tibas full hip
extension head neck and torso all in
line this is a great hip thrust my only
tip would be take a slightly wider
stance maybe a foot a foot wider than
this and then everything would be
[Music]
perfect okay uh now we've got a single
leg hip
thrust
uh again this is a tall bench I think
she could go deeper and touch her butt
to the ground uh but pretty vertical
tibia here that looks good she's
reaching full hip extension she might be
able to squeeze the glute just slightly
higher and raise raise up just a little
more hard to tell there it looks like
full hip extension the the Torso is in a
straight line she's not
overarched uh and the neck stays in
neutral alignment on one single like H
this I like using the bench like this
using the arms to hug the bench but this
looks good I would just possibly say go
down deeper I I should also mention
she's not twisting and rotating so she's
keeping good cor stability this leg can
be straight out or I like to do it
flexed where my knee is bent like that
either one is
fine now we've got a a Sumo deadlift uh
with this Sumo deadlift I would say the
bar is close to shins that's nice I like
to see vertical tibas with sumo
deadlifts hers are angled forward a bit
so she should sit back even more and
force those knees out even more and uh
but the head neck and torso look good
she's keeping a good Arch bar is close
to her body uh so it looks pretty good
um she uses the glutes to lock it out uh
one thing you see those hips shoot up
slightly faster than the knees that's
not that big of a deal I'm not too Nick
nitpicky about that but this is a good
Sumo deadlift only advice is to just sit
back a little more and force those knees
out okay now we've got another Sumo
deadlift and this is great uh you can
see uh when she locks this weight out
look at those divots there that's when
you can really tell they're using the
glutes to lock out the weight head neck
uh torso stay in good position
bar is close to the body squeezing her
glutes to lock the weight out I would
say uh possibly see here those tibas are
angled forward might want to be sitting
back a little more and forcing those
knees out just slightly more but overall
looks
great um anyway that's all for now I
hope you've uh hope you've enjoyed the
video I hope this was helpful for you uh
if people do like this I'm going to do
more this more often so so uh thanks
ladies great job keep working hard uh
it's showing so keep it up and thanks
for the kind words